everyoneactive.com 2015-04-06

# Everyone Active | Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy relates to the entire website for Everyone Active which is the trading name for Sports Leisure Ltd company. The policy is in place to inform users of Everyone Active about the collection, use and sharing of personal information collected through the www.everyoneactive.com (“website”) or other services including SMS, WAP and any mobile phone applications. This privacy policy is designed to protect you, our users, by informing you what personal information is collected, what we do with that information, with whom we share it, and the methods we use to collect and secure it.

This policy may be updated from time to time for any reason with each version applying to information collected whilst it was in place. We will notify all members of any material changes to our Privacy Policy by posting the new policy on our website. By using our website you are consenting to us processing your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. Everyone Active was created to help people achieve their activity goals as well as connect with your friends and people with similar goals. We endeavour to make it easy for you to share information with your friends and people around you but recognise that you may want to prevent other people accessing this information. The default privacy settings in Everyone Active restrict the information displayed in your online profile to your full username and avatar or profile picture (if you choose to upload one) allowing you further opportunities to share additional information should you choose to.

Everyone Active is committed to complying with the Data Protection Acts of 1998 and The Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and any traditional and digital marketing efforts we undertake adhere strictly to their provisions.

These are the basic guidelines we use when processing your personal data:

  1. We maintain secure systems to protect your personal information
  2. We respect your wishes about how we contact you, whether by post, telephone, email or text message
  3. We will not hold your personal information for longer than is necessary;
  4. We will update your information or preferences promptly when you ask us to
  5. We will respond fully to requests from you to see the information that we hold on you

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognises only the consumer's domain name, but not the e-mail address

We collect only the domain name, but not the e-mail address, of visitors to our Web pages, the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, aggregate information on what pages consumers access or visit and information volunteered by the consumer, such as enquiries submitted through the contact form and/or the special offers purchase form.

Therefore any personal data collected or stored by Everyone Active is, processed and stored there under UK Privacy and Data Protection Standards. For the purposes of the Data Protection Act 1998 (“the Act”), the data controller is Everyone Active. By providing your personal information to us you consent to such processing in the UK. The information we collect is used for internal review to improve the content of our Web page.

The Information we collect is used by Everyone Active to contact you for marketing purposes. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by unsubscribing to e-mails sent you.

From time to time, we may notify you by email about products or services we think you might find interesting, and to answer enquiries. If you do not want us to use your email address, please let us know by ticking the relevant box in the permissions page in your profile or by calling us at the number below or e-mailing the support team or writing to us at the above postal address.

If you supply us with your postal address from time to time, you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by ticking the relevant box in the permissions page in your profile or by calling us at the number below or e-mailing the support team or writing to us at the above postal address.

If you supply us with your telephone number from time to time you may receive calls from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such calls, please let us know by ticking the relevant box in the permissions page in your profile or by calling us at the number below or e-mailing the support team or writing to us at the above postal address.

With your permission, we will contact you for marketing purposes to tell you about new products, events, offers & news from Everyone Active and our partners.

Everyone Active reserve the right to store data securely outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) in the future. Such data therefore may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for Everyone Active or one of its approved partners. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your orders, processing of payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data you agree to such transfer, processing and storage.

In order to comply with our obligations under the Act we follow procedures in the storage and disclosure of information that you have given us, to prevent unauthorised access, misuse, alteration or loss of information under our control.

Any payment transactions and password data will be encrypted and you are reminded it is your responsibility not to share your password with others.

You are entitled to request a copy of the data we hold about you for which we may charge a small fee and you have the right to correct any inaccuracies in that data.

If you have any questions or comments about our Privacy Policy or how we use your personal information please contact us at [webmaster@everyoneactive.com](mailto:webmaster@everyoneactive.com?subject=Privacy%20Policy)

## Information Collection and Use

## Data Collection

When you register on and subsequently visit our website you provide us with two types of information:

### Personal information you elect to provide us with in order to enrol on Everyone Active Online

Such information is collected to ensure that we can provide you with the services made available throughout the website, validate your eligibility to join the website, keep in contact with you and to manage your registered account.  
This information may include (but is not limited to) your name, age, email address, telephone number, postal address, your gender and certain health and fitness related data obtained in order to create personalized fitness workouts for you.

### Data collected concerning your use of the website

When you enter Everyone Active we collect your browser type, the search terms you use, IP address, domain from which you are visiting and advertisements on which you click as well as store certain information from your browser using cookies.  
Cookies are pieces of data stored on a user’s computer tied to information about that user. We use session ID cookies to confirm that users are logged in which terminate once the user closes their browser. If you choose to you can allow us to use a persistent cookie to store your login ID and password to make it easier for you to login to the website. This option is not a default setting and it is strongly recommended that this feature is not used on shared computers.

## Contact and Correspondence

When you use Everyone Active you set up a personal profile page which details your friends, networks, groups and events. Should you choose to within the privacy settings on Everyone Active you can also share information relating to your activities, food events, points target and exercise history to either your friends or the wider community.

If you contact us by email or via the website we may keep a record of both your contact information and enquiry and may subsequently use your email address, and any information that you provide us with in your correspondence, to respond to you and deal with your enquiry.

## Inviting Friends and Public Profiles

If you invite friends to join Everyone Active via the ‘refer a friend feature’ we will ask you for contact information for that friend and will invite them to join Everyone Active using your name as a reference. We will send your friend reminders encouraging them to join Everyone Active. If your friend would like to be removed from our database they can do so by emailing the support team below.

If you want to invite people to be your friends within the Everyone Active community you are advised to look at their ‘public’ profile first to find out more about them. If you still want to be their friend you can send a request via the Everyone Active system.

If you later decide to remove that friend from your friends list you can block or remove them in the preferences section.

You should also note that the standard default within Everyone Active online will show a public profile for you which includes (but not limited to) your profile picture, weekly points target, favourite activities and favourite community comments and threads.

If you want to restrict who can see this information you should change your settings in the preferences section. Everyone Active take no responsibility for information shared within the Everyone Active community as a result of this profile page.

## Sharing Information with Third Parties

Everyone Active may from time to time use your profile information without identifying you personally when communicating with other organisations and agents. Such information is aggregated and used to ensure that we provide you with a more personal service. This feature, for example, allows Everyone Active to ensure that any advertisements featured on the website are more likely to be relevant and of interest to you.

Everyone Active will never provide your personal contact information to third parties without your prior consent.

## Posting Information

You post all content (as defined in the Terms of Use) on Everyone Active at your own risk and we must make you aware that no privacy measures are impenetrable. Everyone Active is not able to control the actions of other Users with whom you may choose to share information therefore we are not able to guarantee that information you share on the website will not be viewed by unauthorised users. You should also be aware that even after you close your account or remove personal information copies of user account information may remain viewable in cached and archived pages and if other users have stored your personal user content.

If you are aware of any improper use of personal information on Everyone Active please report this to the support team below.

## Children

Within Everyone Active Online we do collect personal information from individuals under the age of 16 and therefore we do allow such persons to register on the website.

If you are under 16 & registered & you wish to post information about yourself in any Everyone Active forums or community areas you must gain your parents consent, Everyone Active accept no liability.

Within Everyone Active Leisure Centre’s if you are under 12 years old you must have your parent or guardian's consent before you provide personal information to us. We do not wish to collect any personal information without this permission

## Information Sharing

Everyone Active use certain trusted third parties to perform certain functions in order to deliver our service. These service include, but are not limited to; web hosting and web service management, server hosting, data storage and direct marketing.

Everyone Active will share certain personal information about its users with these third parties to allow them to perform these functions and all are subject to binding contractual obligations requiring them to maintain the privacy of such data.

## Links to Other Sites

Everyone Active may, from time to time, contain links to and from external websites, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to these sites please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. We strongly advise that you check these policies before you submit and personal data to these websites.

## Community

When creating new ‘Nattergories’ on the Natter section of the website the system will automatically make those conversions public unless you indicate that you want them to be a private conversation.

## Advertising

Adverts which appear on Everyone Active are monitored and controlled by Everyone Active directly and, as such, you can be assured that these companies are not monitoring IP address information or installing additional cookies on your computer.

## Cookies

Visiting Everyone Active websites with your browser settings adjusted to accept cookies tells us that you want to use Everyone Active products and services and that you consent to our use of cookies and other technologies to provide them to you as described in this notice. See below for information on how to modify the settings in your browser to notify you when you receive a new cookie and disable cookies altogether.

### What are cookies and how do they work?

Cookies are small bits of text that are downloaded to your computer or mobile device when you visit a website. Your browser sends these cookies back to the website every time you visit the site again, so it can recognise you and can then tailor what you see on the screen.

### What do you use cookies for?

Cookies are an important part of the internet. They make using websites much smoother and affect lots of the useful features of websites. There are many different uses for cookies, but they fall into four main groups.

#### 1\. Cookies that are need to provide the service you have asked for

Some cookies are essential so you can move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you've asked for can't be provided. These cookies don't gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you've been on the internet. Here are some examples of essential cookies.

  * Keeping you logged in during your visit; without cookies you might have to log in on every page you go to.
  * When you add something to the online shopping basket, cookies make sure it's still there when you get to the checkout.
  * Some are session cookies which make it possible to navigate through the website smoothly. However these are automatically deleted after you close your web browser.

#### 2\. Improving your browsing experience

These cookies allow the website to remember choices you make, such as your language or region and they provide improved features. Here are a few examples of just some of the ways that cookies are used to improve your experience on our websites.

  * Remembering your preferences and settings, including marketing preferences, such as opting in or out of marketing emails.
  * Remembering if you've filled in a survey, so you're not asked to do it again.
  * Remembering if you've been to the site before. If you are a first-time user, you might see different content to a regular user.
  * Restricting the number of times you're shown a particular advertisement. This is sometimes called 'frequency capping'.
  * Showing you information that's relevant to products of ours that you have.
  * Giving you access to content provided by social-media sites like Facebook or Twitter.
  * Showing 'related article' links that are relevant to the page you're looking at.
  * Remembering a location you've entered such as weather forecasts.

#### 3\. Functionality

These cookies allow users to customise how a website looks for them: they can remember usernames, language preferences and regions, and can be used to provide more personal services like local weather reports and traffic news.

#### 4\. Analytics

We like to keep track of what pages and links are popular and which ones don't get used so much to help us keep our sites relevant and up to date. It's also very useful to be able to identify trends of how people navigate (find their way through) our sites and if they get 'error messages' from web pages. This group of cookies, often called 'analytics cookies' are used to gather this information. These cookies don't collect information that identifies you. The information collected is anonymous and is grouped with the information from everyone else’s cookies. We can then see the overall patterns of usage rather than any one person’s activity. Analytics cookies only record activity on the site you are on and they are only used to improve how a website works. Some of our websites and some of the emails you might get from us also contain small invisible images known as 'web beacons' or 'tracking pixels'. These are used to count the number of times the page or email has been viewed and allows us to measure the effectiveness of its marketing and emails. These web beacons are anonymous and don't contain or collect any information that identifies you. We also use 'affiliate' cookies. Some of our web pages will contain promotional links to other companies’ sites. If you follow one of these links and then register with or buy something from that other site, a cookie is sometimes used to tell that other site that you came from one of our sites. That other site may then pay us a small amount for the successful referral. This works using a cookie. For more information, see the [Internet Advertising Bureau's guide about how affiliate marketing works](http://www.iab-performance-marketing-explained.net/).

## Cookies and Browser Settings

The Help menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie and how to disable cookies altogether. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, such as Flash cookies, by changing the add-on's settings or visiting the website of its manufacturer.

## Enquiries and registered office

This website is operated Everyone Active, whose registered office & head office is below. To get in touch with our head office please contact:

Sports and Leisure Management Ltd  
3 Watling Drive  
Sketchley Meadows  
Hinckley  
Leicestershire  
LE10 3EY  
Telephone 01455 890508

Registered in England No.220408
